ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田鐘人，作畫：阿部司）
29 YEARS FROM THE DEATH OF HIMMEL THE HERO
（勇者欣梅爾逝世的29年後）
THE SCHWER MOUNTAINS IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
（北方諸國，修維亞山脈）
Mistress Frieren is about to fall asleep.
芙莉蓮大人要睡著了
-She fell asleep. -Oh well. I'll carry her on my back.
-她睡著了 -沒辦法，我背著她走吧
But you have your axe.
但修塔爾克大人的斧頭…
But my hands are free.
可是妳看，我的手是空著的
-I'll carry her on my back. -Why?
-還是我來背吧 -為什麼？
Just because.
沒有為什麼
In the end, the king only gave us ten copper coins.
最後國王只給了我們十枚銅幣
-What a cheapskate. -It can't be helped.
-真小氣 -那也是沒辦法的事
Up until now, many heroes have departed
至今為止 出發前去討伐魔王的勇者們
and failed to defeat the Demon King.
無一倖免，全都失敗了
Well, earning our own travel expenses by completing
算啦，老實地靠自己去接受任務委託
subjugation quests isn't so bad.
賺自己的旅費也沒那麼糟糕
-It makes it more like an adventure. -You're right.
-這樣更像在冒險 -說得沒錯
Hey, that sword is the Hero's Blade.
是說，那把劍是勇者之劍嗎？
It's a replica.
是仿冒品
I once saved a peddler who came to my village from a monster
以前有個來村子裡做生意的商人 我從魔物手中救下了他
and he gave this to me saying, "To the hero of the future."
他就送了這把劍給我 說是送給未來的勇者
He was just playing.
就是隨口說說，哄哄小孩子罷了
-Is that why you became a hero? -No.
-那就是你成為勇者的契機嗎？ -不是
There was an annoying kid named Heiter in the orphanage.
是因為孤兒院裡有個 叫做海塔的煩人小鬼
And he told me,
他對我說
"Since you only have a fake sword, you can only become a fake hero."
“反正你拿的是把假劍 充其量也只能當個假勇者”
"Then I'll become a real hero and show you."
“既然如此 我就成為真正的勇者讓你看看”
That's what I thought.
我那時就是這麼想的
One day, I will get a hold of the real Hero's Blade
總有一天，我會拿到真正的勇者之劍
and defeat the Demon King.
然後打敗魔王
But time sure is merciless.
但歲月真是無情啊
Heiter, the one who was running his mouth,
當年說出那些話的海塔
is now a fake priest who does nothing but drink.
如今變成了只會喝酒的假僧侶
I'm a real priest.
我是真僧侶喔
-It was just a dream… -Mistress Frieren.
-原來是夢… -芙莉蓮大人
You're finally awake.
您終於醒了
This scenery is like déjà vu.
這景色很有既視感呢
-I must still be dreaming. -Wouldn't that be nice.
-我一定是還在作夢 -真是作夢就好囉
I took the mountain's weather too lightly.
之前太過小看山上的天氣了
Keep going north.
繼續往北走
The village we're headed to should be there.
我們要去的村子應該就在那裡
Okay.
我知道了
Mistress Frieren, can you walk on your own?
芙莉蓮大人可以自己走路嗎？
-No. -I see.
-不行 -這樣啊
You smell good.
好香喔
Jeez…
真是的…
You must be tired from carrying her the whole time.
妳背她這麼久一定累了吧
Fern, I'll take over.
費倫，換我來吧
Pervert…
變態
Why?
為什麼？
The blizzard is dying down now.
暴風雪平靜下來了
I was about to freeze to death.
差點就要凍死了
A village actually exists this deep in the mountains?
這種深山裡竟然真的有村落？
We were waiting for you, Mistress Frieren.
恭候多時了，芙莉蓮大人
You're the current village chief? How young…
妳是現任村長？真年輕
Yes, I am the 49th village chief. It's hereditary.
是的，我是第49代村長 村長是世襲制的
Welcome to the Village of the Sword.
歡迎各位來到劍的故鄉
There was a destroyed cabin outside the village.
村外有間被摧毀的小屋
We used to use that as a hunting cabin.
是以前當作狩獵小屋用的地方
-The Lord of the mountains did that. -Lord?
-那是山主幹的 -山主？
Was there such a thing here?
這裡原本有那種東西嗎？
So this is the Village of the Sword?
這裡就是劍的故鄉？
You know about it, Master Stark?
修塔爾克大人知道這裡嗎？
It's the village that protected the Hero's Blade.
這裡就是守護勇者之劍的村子
In the sanctuary near the village,
離這個村子不遠的地方有處聖域
there was the Hero's Blade, which was said to be bestowed by the Goddess.
據說女神大人 親授的勇者之劍就在那裡
All sorts of heroes
歷史上的各路英雄豪傑
tried to pull it out throughout history, but it never budged.
都曾經試圖把它拔出來過 但它紋絲不動
That was until 80 years ago.
直到八十年前
There was a legend regarding that…
我記得有個傳說…
The only one who can pull out the Hero's Blade
能將勇者之劍拔出來的人
is the hero destined to stop the great calamity that will destroy the world.
就是能夠阻止巨大災難 毀滅世界的唯一勇者
That's it.
就是那個
So Master Himmel is the one who pulled out the sword?
拔出那把劍的就是欣梅爾大人吧？
That's right.
沒錯
It's a pretty famous story. You've never heard of it?
這個故事相當有名，妳沒聽過嗎？
No, Master Heiter never told me.
沒有，海塔大人從沒跟我說過
Here it is.
就是這裡了
So warm…
好溫暖…
This is unacceptable, Mistress Frieren.
“話說芙莉蓮大人這樣很過分耶
You promised to return in half a century.
明明說好了半世紀之後就會回來
Normally, I'm mild-tempered, but I am mad about this.
我平時也算脾氣溫和 但這件事我真的很生氣”
Those were the last words of my grandma, the chief two generations before me.
以上是前前代村長，祖母大人的遺言
I said it'll be fine for another 80 years.
我說過再過個八十年也不會有問題啊
The people of this village who have been protecting the Hero's Blade
村裡的人世世代代都在守護勇者之劍
should be able to protect themselves.
應該也有足夠的能力自保
That may be true.
話是這麼說沒錯
But we need you to do your job too.
但我們也需要您完成自己的職責
-What do you mean by "your job"? -Getting rid of monsters.
-“職責”指的是什麼？ -討伐魔物啦
Monsters regularly show up around this village.
每隔一段時間 魔物就會出現在村子周圍
Recently, the Lord of the mountains has been acting up too.
尤其是最近山主活動頻繁 情況真的很糟糕
I guess we'll start tomorrow.
那明天就出發吧
I'd rather get this out of the way.
麻煩的事情還是要早點解決為好
There are so many monsters so close to the village.
離村子這麼近的地方 竟然有這麼多的魔物
Why didn't you hire
情況都已經這麼糟了
other adventurers if your situation was this bad?
妳怎麼不發布 討伐委託給其他冒險者呢？
We would have loved to but…
我們當然也想，只不過…
Himmel is a hero, after all.
畢竟欣梅爾是英雄啊
There are seriously so many monsters.
話說那邊的魔物真的好多啊
They're assembling by that cave.
全都聚集在那個山洞前
Frieren! This is--
芙莉蓮，這是…
It's the Lord.
是山主
I see. No wonder I didn't know about you.
原來如此，難怪我不認識你
You're a newcomer.
是新來的啊
You think you're a lord after just 80 years?
才過了八十年就自認是老大了？
Stark, you can still move, right?
修塔爾克，你還能動吧？
You sure know how to use people!
妳還真是會使喚人啊！
Good job.
做得好
Now my job is done.
這樣我就完成職責了
Frieren, care to explain?
芙莉蓮，這是怎麼回事？
That's the Hero's Blade.
那是勇者之劍吧
This is what attracts the monsters here.
魔物會聚集在此都是被它吸引過來的
Monsters can't get through the sanctuary's strong barrier,
聖域因為有強大的結界保護 所以魔物無法進入
but they can't resist their urge to destroy that.
但牠們依舊按捺不住 想要摧毀它的衝動
That's how scared they are of the Hero's Blade.
牠們就是如此懼怕勇者之劍
That's not what I'm talking about.
我說的不是這個
Yeah…
沒錯…
Himmel wasn't able to pull out this sword.
欣梅爾當年沒能拔出這把劍
This time's hero wasn't the real one either, huh?
這次來的也不是真的勇者嗎？
Himmel…
欣梅爾…
What's wrong with a fake hero?
有什麼關係？假勇者又怎麼樣？
I will defeat the Demon King and restore this world's peace.
我會打敗魔王，讓世界恢復和平
Then being "real" or "fake" will not matter anymore.
這樣一來，真真假假也就都無所謂了
And Himmel accomplished just that.
而欣梅爾確實兌現了他的諾言
He showed that he could save the world without that sword.
即使沒有那把劍 他也證明了他可以拯救世界
He's a real hero.
他是真正的勇者
Then why is that fact being hidden?
那為什麼要隱藏真相呢？
That was done by the people who want to idolize Himmel.
應該是那些 自己想把欣梅爾英雄化的人做的吧
Unappealing stories like how he couldn't
對於勇者來說，他並不需要
pull out the Hero's Blade are unnecessary for a hero.
沒能拔出勇者之劍的勇者 這段不吸引人的故事吧
Heroes are always
後代世人總是
overly romanticized by future generations.
太過於美化那些英雄了
And in time, the truth becomes completely obscured.
隨著時光流逝，真相也逐漸被掩蓋
I knew you'd come through for us, Mistress Frieren.
“我一直深信著 芙莉蓮大人一定會再來這裡找我們
Thanks a bunch.
超級感謝”
That's also my grandma's last words.
這也是我祖母大人的遺言
What kind of last words did your grandma leave?
妳祖母留的這都是什麼遺言啊？
Well then, see you in another half century.
好吧，那就半世紀之後見了
Next time, don't be late.
下次可別遲到囉
29 YEARS FROM THE DEATH OF HIMMEL THE HERO
（勇者欣梅爾逝世的29年後）
APPETIT REGION IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
（北方諸國，亞佩提特地區）
Once we drop off our things at the inn, everyone's free until nighttime.
在旅店放好行李之後 就自由活動到晚上
I haven't seen a town in so long. I can finally relax.
好久沒看到城鎮了 終於可以好好放鬆一下
What are you going to do?
芙莉蓮大人，您打算要做什麼呢？
Do you want to shop around together?
要不要一起逛街買東西？
I'm good. I'll relax here and read my grimoires.
不用了，我就在這裡休息看魔導書吧
Really? Then I'll go by myself.
真的嗎？那我就自己去了
Oh, that reminds me…
啊，對了
Today is Stark's 18th birthday.
今天是修塔爾克的十八歲生日
Why don't you tell me these things beforehand?
這種事怎麼不提前跟我說呢？
I don't have anything ready.
我什麼都沒準備
Just buy something in the town.
在鎮上買點東西送他不就行了？
I don't know what Master Stark wants.
我不清楚修塔爾克大人想要什麼
You're so unprepared, Fern.
妳還真是措手不及呢，費倫
It's your fault, you know.
這都是芙莉蓮大人的錯啊
By the way,
話說回來，芙莉蓮大人
what are you planning to give to him?
您打算送他什麼禮物？
It's special.
是很特別的禮物喔
A potion that only melts clothes.
只會讓衣服融化的藥劑
When it comes to men,
只要是男人
they're happy just getting something like this.
收到這種東西都會很高興
That's what Master told me.
這是師父告訴我的
What? You're interested in it too?
怎麼？妳對這個也有興趣嗎？
When you bought this obscene potion
您買了這罐下流藥水時
did I not tell you to return it?
我不是讓您拿去退掉了嗎？
Forget about you.
芙莉蓮大人愛怎樣都隨便您好了
This potion was valuable, you know…
這罐藥水很貴的耶
What should I give him?
這下禮物要怎麼辦呢？
I forgot I had this.
都忘了有這個東西
I have no choice but to get information from him directly.
果然只能直接去問他了
Although it'd be very obvious…
儘管這樣問的意圖很明顯…
Master Stark.
修塔爾克大人
He went out?
他出去了？
A warrior carrying an axe on his back?
揹著把斧頭的戰士？
He helped me push this cart.
他剛剛幫我推了貨車呢
I believe he went toward the plaza.
我記得他往廣場那邊走了
He was just playing with us.
他剛剛在跟我們玩
He helped him down from the tree.
他幫我把貓咪從樹上救了下來
He stopped a cow who was out of control.
他剛剛攔下了一頭發狂的牛
He's helped many people.
他幫了好多人
That was very rude of Mistress Frieren.
芙莉蓮大人真是太失禮了
There's no way Master Stark would be happy getting such a perverted potion.
修塔爾克大人怎麼可能會因為 收到那種下流藥水而開心嘛！
Master Stark…
修塔爾克大人…
That cloud looks like boobs.
那朵雲看起來好像胸部
He is a pervert.
這個變態
Are you serious? That one looks like poop!
不會吧？那朵看起來像大便耶！
No, he's just childish.
不，他只是幼稚而已
-I've got to tell Fern later. -How am I supposed to react to that?
-等一下跟費倫說吧 -那我該做何反應啊？
Master Stark.
修塔爾克大人
Fern, great timing!
費倫，來得正好！
That cloud…
那朵雲…
Sorry, never mind.
抱歉，當我沒說
-Um… -Want to take a walk?
-那…那個… -要不要一起走走？
Yes.
是
Hey, why are you mad? Did I do something?
妳幹嘛生氣？我做錯什麼了嗎？
How should I bring it up?
該怎麼說出口呢？
I'll apologize.
我道歉就是了嘛
No matter how I do it, it'll be obvious.
不管怎麼問都會很明顯
Might as well ask him straight out.
乾脆直接問他吧
Master Stark, is there anything you want?
修塔爾克大人，你有想要的東西嗎？
Why?
怎麼這麼問？
Because today is your birthday.
因為今天是你的生日
Is it? What does that have to do with what I want?
是嗎？那跟我想要什麼有什麼關係？
It's for your birthday present.
是給你的生日禮物
What? You're giving me something?
什麼？妳要送我什麼東西？
Never mind. You're being annoying so I won't give you anything.
實在是讓人火大，還是不送了
No, I wasn't trying to be funny or anything.
不是，我不是在開玩笑之類的
I've never gotten any presents on my birthday before.
我從來沒有收過生日禮物
I never received anything from my late family members or my master.
不管是死去的家人也好 師父也好，他們從來沒送過
So I thought that's how it was.
所以我以為生日就是這樣過的
Not even your family?
連故鄉的家人也沒送過？
-Was that your culture? -No…
-那裡的風俗就是這樣嗎？ -不是
They probably just didn't care about me.
他們大概只是沒把我當回事吧
My hometown was a village of warriors.
我出身於戰士之村
Weak people didn't belong.
那裡不是弱者的容身之處
You let a mere monster do this to you?
區區魔物居然讓你們變成這樣？
Try to be like Stoltz. Not only is he unharmed,
學學修特爾茲吧，他不只毫髮無傷
but he also doesn't have a speck of blood or dirt on him.
身上連一點塵土或血跡都沒沾到
A spotless white cloak is the sign
沒有沾上半點汙垢的白色披風
of this village's strongest warrior.
是這個村子最強戰士的象徵
Stoltz, you are this village's pride and joy.
修特爾茲，你是這個村子的驕傲
Of course, Dad.
那是當然的，父親
Stark, on the other hand, is such a failure.
相較之下，修塔爾克真是個失敗品
Despite how much he trains every day,
不管他每天如何努力修練
he hasn't been able to fight a monster even once.
卻一次都無法跟魔物戰鬥
It's starting to rain. Let's go.
要開始下雨了，回去吧
I'll go train my good-for-nothing brother.
我去好好教教他
Don't bully him too much.
別太苛求他了
I'm heading back. I don't want to waste my time.
我回去了，我才不想浪費時間
Stark.
修塔爾克
Brother…
大哥…
I'm sorry…
對不起…
Good concentration.
專注力很好呢
I bet you'll become strong.
你以後一定會變得很強
But your stance can use some work.
但是姿勢需要再修正一下
Actually, my older brother was the only one who was different.
說起來，只有大哥他不一樣
But…
不過…
When my hometown was attacked by demons,
在魔族攻擊我的故鄉時
I still abandoned him and ran away.
我還是拋棄了那樣的大哥逃走了
No wonder my family never celebrated my birthday.
也難怪我家人從未替我慶祝生日
I'm a failure who can only run away.
我就是個只會逃跑的失敗品
If it were Himmel, he wouldn't have run away.
換作是欣梅爾，他一定不會逃跑
Master Stark,
修塔爾克大人
let's go pick out your present.
我們去挑生日禮物吧
The past doesn't matter.
跟過去的事情沒有關係
Stark, the warrior whom I've seen up until now,
至今為止我所看到的戰士修塔爾克
has never run away even once.
可是一次都沒有逃跑過喔
I might run away some day.
也許哪天我就會逃跑了
We won't let you get away.
我們不會讓你逃走的
-But I… -If you don't come, I'll choose myself.
-可是我… -你不來的話，我就自己選了
All right, fine.
我知道了啦
-Okay, I choose this. -No, that's too expensive.
-那我選這個… -太貴了，不行
Yes ma'am.
遵命
Welcome back. What took you so long?
歡迎回來，怎麼那麼慢？
Mistress Frieren, what is up with these ridiculously huge Hamburg steaks?
芙莉蓮大人 這些超大的漢堡排是要做什麼？
What are you saying? A birthday isn't a birthday without these.
妳在說什麼啊？ 過生日沒有漢堡排就不算數了
Master never gave me a present,
師父從沒送過我生日禮物
but he always made me a birthday Hamburg steak.
但是一定會為我準備超大的漢堡排
What is this about?
這是怎麼回事啊？
-Stark, Eisen never told you? -About what?
-修塔爾克，艾冉沒告訴過你啊？ -告訴我什麼？
Warriors can be so difficult.
戰士還真是很笨拙
You're in no position to say that.
您沒有資格說這種話吧
Yeah, I'm also difficult, so I know what it's like.
是啊，我也很笨拙 所以我能明白他的心情
We're stupid, aren't we?
我們真的是很笨呢
We should know that we have to put our feelings into words.
明明應該要開口 才能傳達自己的心意給對方知道
This is…
這個啊…
Why do you make a ridiculously huge
說起來，你怎麼每逢誰的生日
Hamburg steak whenever it's someone's birthday?
就準備這種超大的漢堡排？
This is a custom from the region I'm from.
這是我故鄉的習俗
It's a gift you give to reward a warrior who has worked very hard.
這個禮物是用來 犒勞很拼命努力的戰士
Think of it as a birthday present from me.
就當作是我送的生日禮物好了
But Eisen, we're not warriors.
可是艾冉，我們不是戰士
Anyone who has worked hard is a warrior.
只要是努力過的人都是戰士
-Really? -Who knows?
-是這樣嗎？ -誰知道？
A warrior who has worked very hard?
“很拼命努力的戰士”？
Brother, what are you making?
大哥，你在做什麼？
Hamburg steak. It's your birthday, isn't it?
漢堡排啊，今天不是你生日嗎？
Don't tell Dad or anyone.
不要告訴爸爸他們喔
Run away, Stark.
快逃，修塔爾克
You must live.
你一定要活下去
Eisen gave me the recipe.
食譜是艾冉給的
How is it? Does it taste good?
怎麼樣？好吃嗎？
Yeah.
好吃
Also, this…
還有這個
There's still a little left.
裡面還剩一點…
Don't make me pour it on your head again.
芙莉蓮大人 是要我再把它倒在妳頭上嗎？
Huh? What's that?
什麼？那是什麼東西？
It has nothing to do with you.
跟修塔爾克大人一點關係都沒有
-It's a valuable potion. -What kind?
-是很貴重的藥水 -哪種藥水啊？
-Pervert. -Huh? Why?
-變態 -咦？為什麼？
-Why are you calling me that?
-所以說到底幹嘛這樣叫我？
-Himmel! -I got a nosebleed.
-欣梅爾！ -我流鼻血了
-Alcohol is the best medicine. -What about it?
-“酒為百藥之長” -這個怎麼樣？
-Adults use dirty tricks. -I like older women.
-大人都很骯髒 -我喜歡大姐姐啊
"Aversion to One's Own Kind."
《同類厭惡》
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯：洪貞韻